Guide to the Burney Family Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Burney Family Collection, Series I
  - BURNEY, CHARLES, MUS. D., 1726-1814
    - Letter to William Crotch, 1805 Nov 4 (Box 4, Folder 243)
    - Letter to Mrs. Davies, [1786] Feb 17 (Box 4, Folder 244)
    - Letter to Rev. Mr. Davy, [pre-1797] (Box 4, Folder 245)
    - Letters to Miss Hamilton, 1785 Feb-Jun (Box 4, Folder 246)
    - Letter to Denis Diderot, [1771 Mar] (Box 4, Folder 247)
    - Letter to Jeffrey Ekins, Dean of Carlisle, [ca. 1785] (Box 4, Folder 248)
    - Letter to Charles Long, Baron Farnborough, [post 1809 Oct 16] (Box 4, Folder 249)
    - Letters to Mrs. Fermor and Mrs. Willis, [ca. 1807] (Box 4, Folder 250)
    - Letter to Mrs. Fermor, [post 1807] (Box 4, Folder 251)
    - Letters to John Flaxman, 1806, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 252)
    - Letter to Edward S. Foss, 1813 Jan 19 (Box 4, Folder 253)
    - Letter to Briggs Fontaine, 1776 Apr 5 (Box 4, Folder 254)
    - Letter to John Gillies M.D., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 255)
    - Letter to "the Baron" (J.P. Brissot de Warville), [post 1795] (Box 4, Folder 255)
    - Letter to Mr. Grant, [ca. 1777] (Box 4, Folder 256)
    - Letters to Ralph Griffiths, 1796-1802 (Box 4, Folder 256a)
    - Letter to [William Colman], 1779 Oct (Box 4, Folder 257)
    - Letters to Miss Louisa M. Harris, [1807?]-[post 1808] (Box 4, Folder 258)
    - Letter to Mrs. Cecilia Maria Henslow, 1804 Apr 30 (Box 4, Folder 259)
    - Letters to Sir William Herschel, 1797-98 (Box 4, Folder 260)
    - Letter to the Rev. Sam Hoole, 1804 Oct 23 (Box 4, Folder 261)
    - Letters to Johann Christian Hüttner, 1802-07 (Box 4, Folder 262)
    - Letters to Johann Christian Hüttner, 1808 Feb-May (Box 4, Folder 263)
    - Letters to Johann Christian Hüttner, 1808 Jun (Box 4, Folder 264)
    - Letters to Johann Christian Hüttner, 1808 Jul (Box 4, Folder 265)
    - Letters to Johann Christian Hüttner, 1812 May (Box 4, Folder 266)
    - Letter to Mrs. John Hunter, [1802] (Box 4, Folder 267)
    - Letters to [Elizabeth Iremonger], 1799-[1814?] (Box 4, Folder 268)
    - Letter to Samuel Johnson, 1755 Apr 14 (Box 4, Folder 269)
    - Letter to Mr. Jones, 1802 Jun 12 (Box 4, Folder 270)
    - Letter to Sir James Lake, 1783 May 25 (Box 4, Folder 271)
    - Letters to [Christian Latrobe], 1784-85 (Box 4, Folder 272)
    - Letters to Christian Latrobe, 1786-87 (Box 4, Folder 273)
    - Letters to Christian Latrobe, 1788-[90] (Box 4, Folder 274)
    - Letters to Christian Latrobe, 1791-98 (Box 4, Folder 275)
    - Letters to Christian Latrobe, 1799-1804 (Box 4, Folder 276)
    - Letters to Christian Latrobe, 1805, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 277)
    - Letter to Joachim Le Breton, [1812] (Box 4, Folder 278)
    - Letters to Dr. James Lind, 1774 (Box 4, Folder 279)
    - Letter to William Lock, Jr., 1800 Aug 13 (Box 4, Folder 280)
    - Letter to Viscount Lowther, 1804 July (Box 4, Folder 281)
    - Letter to Lady Elizabeth Lowther, [ca. 1807?] (Box 4, Folder 282)
    - Letter to Samuel Lysons, 1811 Oct 15 (Box 4, Folder 283)
    - Letters to Edmond Malone, n.d., 1804 (Box 4, Folder 284)
    - Letter to Lady Manvers, 1809-12, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 285)
    - Letter to [Giovanni Battista] Martini, 1778 Jun 29 (Box 4, Folder 286)
    - Letter to William Mason, 1770-95 (Box 4, Folder 287)
    - Letters to Thomas James Matthias, 1806 Jun 17 (Box 4, Folder 288)
    - Letter to Mme. (Regina) Mingotti, 1774 May 3 (Box 4, Folder 289)
    - Note to Dr. William Hunter, [1774] Jul 29 (Box 4, Folder 290)
    - Letters to Garrett Wellesley, Earl of Mornington, 1776 Feb-May (Box 4, Folder 291)
    - Letter to Benjamin Moseley, 1799 Jan 26 (Box 4, Folder 292)
    - Letter to Brownlow North, Bishop of Winchester, 1811 Apr 18 (Box 4, Folder 293)
    - Letter to Mrs. (Anne) Ord, [1807] Dec 26 (Box 4, Folder 294)
    - Letter to James Ord, 1808 May 7 (Box 4, Folder 295)
    - Letter to Lord Orford, [1783] (Box 4, Folder 296)
    - Letters to Mrs. Park, 1791-1813 (Box 4, Folder 297)
    - Letter to Sir William Parsons, 1799 Mar 14 (Box 4, Folder 298)
    - Letter to Molesworth Phillips, 1791 Sep 13 (Box 4, Folder 299)
    - Letter to Susan Burney Phillips, 1783-95 (Box 4, Folder 300)
    - Letters to Hester Lynch (Salusbury) Thrale Piozzi, 1779-1807 (Box 4, Folder 301)
    - Letter to Humphrey Repton, 1788 Nov (Box 4, Folder 302)
    - Letter to Messrs. George and John Robinson, 1804 Nov 2 (Box 4, Folder 303)
    - Letter to Francesco Roncaglia, 1778 Oct 6 (Box 4, Folder 304)
    - Letter to Matthew Raper, [1777 Sep] (Box 5, Folder 305)
    - Letter to the Royal Academy, [ca. 1807-12] (Box 5, Folder 306)
    - Letter to Jean Jacques Rousseau, [ca. 1776] (Box 5, Folder 307)
    - Letter to Lord Sandwich, 1778 Nov 22 (Box 5, Folder 308)
    - Letter to J. Schubach, 1779 Feb 12 (Box 5, Folder 309)
    - Letter to Leonard Smelt, 1786 Jul 21 (Box 5, Folder 310)
    - Letters to Mrs. Greenwood Solvyns, 1812, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 311)
    - Letter to Jean Baptiste Antoine Suard, 1776 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 312)
    - Letter to Thomas Twining, 1796, 1799 (Box 5, Folder 313)
    - Letter to Richard Twining, [1804] Aug 13 (Box 5, Folder 314)
    - Letters to Thomas Twining, n.d., [1792] (Box 5, Folder 315)
    - Letter to [Miss Upton], [post 1800 Dec 8] (Box 5, Folder 316)
    - Letters to Joseph Cooper Walker, 1789-1803 (Box 5, Folder 317)
    - Letter to Dr. Warton, 1772 (Box 5, Folder 318)
    - Letter to Samuel Wesley, [ca. 1802]-[08] (Box 5, Folder 319)
    - Letter to [Charles Davy], 1774 Nov 3 (Box 5, Folder 320)
    - Letter to unnamed recipient, [1790] (Box 5, Folder 321)
    - Letter to Dr. Parry, [1802] Apr 22 (Box 5, Folder 322)
    - Letter to unnamed recipient, [ca. 1804-06] (Box 5, Folder 323)
    - Letter to [Sir Joshua Reynolds], [pre-1806]-[ca. 1780 Apr 24] (Box 5, Folder 324)
    - Letter to unnamed recipient, [1806?] (Box 5, Folder 325)
    - Letter to unnamed recipient, [post 1807 Dec 25] (Box 5, Folder 326)
    - Letter to a French friend, 1811 Apr (Box 5, Folder 327)
    - Acc't of the death of my poor friend Bewley sent to the papers, [1783 Sep] (Box 5, Folder 328)
    - [Anecdote of Johnson and Boswell]: holograph (Box 5, Folder 329)
    - Anniversary for Octr. 2d 1795: holograph poem (Box 5, Folder 330)
    - Argument of Dante's Inferno: holograph, [ca. 1765] (Box 5, Folder 331)
    - Astronomy, an historical and didactic poem: holograph poem, [ca. 1796] (Box 5, Folder 332)
    - Certificate as "Correspondant: Institut de France", 1810 Apr 28 (Box 5, Folder 333)
    - Doggrel Dialogue: holograph verse, 1801 Dec 29 (Box 5, Folder 334)
    - Elegy on the Death of a Friend: holograph, [1783] (Box 5, Folder 335)
    - Errata in The Present States of Music: holograph, [1771] (Box 5, Folder 336)
    - In Memory of Elizabeth Burney: holograph verse, 1796 Oct (Box 5, Folder 337)
    - In Memory of Susanna Phillips: holograph verse, 1800 (Box 5, Folder 338)
    - Introduction to his Memoirs: holograph, 1782 (Box 5, Folder 339)
    - Letterbook: 16 leaves extracted from a letter-book headed Musical Correspondence, 1772-78 (Box 5, Folder 340)
    - Twining letter-book no. 2, 1773-75 (Box 5, Folder 341)
    - Twining letter-book no. 3, 1776-82 (Box 5, Folder 342)
    - Twining letter-book no. 4, [post 1829] (Box 5, Folder 343)
    - Letters to and from Thomas Twining, 1782-96 (Box 5, Folder 344)
    - Copies of letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1778-82 (Box 5, Folder 345)
    - Note on Evelina in unkown hand, [post 1777] (Box 5, Folder 346)
    - Literary notes: holograph copy of Chapter XII, from an unidentified author, on Greek tragedy, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 347)
    - Memoirs: fragmentary remains, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 348)
    - Memorandum for a letter to Fanny Burney d'Arblay, 1814 Mar (Box 5, Folder 349)
    - Memorandum: autograph notes on William Windham (Box 5, Folder 350)
    - Memorandum of expenses incident to the prosecution of Thomas Hancock: holograph (Box 5, Folder 351)
    - Memoranda: holograph, consisting of miscellaneous notes, musical, historical, etc. (Box 5, Folder 352)
    - Musical notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 353)
    - Musical Queries for China, [1774] (Box 5, Folder 354)
    - New Year's Ode: holograph verse to Fanny Burney, 1813 Jan (Box 5, Folder 355)
    - Notes for the History of Music, 1801, 1803 (Box 5, Folder 356)
    - Notes on Haydn's Creation, 1800 (Box 5, Folder 357)
    - Notes on Hüttner's account of China, [ca. 1797] (Box 5, Folder 358)
    - Notes on Irish music, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 359)
    - Notes on syncopation, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 360)
    - On My Wife's Birth Day, 1777 Oct 20 (Box 5, Folder 361)
    - Poem on Astronomy, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 362)
    - Poetical notebook, [ca. 1775-76] (Box 5, Folder 363)
    - Receipt signed: for music lessons given to Miss Hoare, 1779 Sep 30 (Box 5, Folder 364)
    - Memorandum: holograph, consisting of extracts copied from letters written to him by Samuel Johnson, [ca. 1784] (Box 5, Folder 365)
    - St. Peter and the Minstrel, a Tale: poem (Box 5, Folder 366)
    - Signature, on letter fragment, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 367)
    - Song, from the French: holograph, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 368)
    - Speech at the Royal Society of Musicians, 1784 Sep 12 (Box 5, Folder 369)
    - To the Association at the Crown and Anchor, [ca. 1790-94] (Box 5, Folder 370)
    - Passport (French) issued to Dr. Burney, 1785 Jul 28 (Box 5, Folder 371)
    - Portraits, etc., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 372)
    - To the Morning Herald, 1782 (Box 5, Folder 373)
    - Tour in France, 1770, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 374)
    - Verses to Fanny Burney, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 375)
    - Voucher for travel from London to Paris, 1785 Jun 28 (Box 5, Folder 376)
  - BURNEY, CHARLES, D.D., 1757-1817
    - Letter to the Aberdeen Jounal, 1779 May 24 (Box 6, Folder 377)
    - Letters to [Arthur] Aikin, [1792]-93 (Box 6, Folder 378)
    - Letters to Frances Burney d'Arblay, [ca. 1767]-[ca. 1779] (Box 6, Folder 379)
    - Letter to his sisters, Frances, Susanna, and Charlotte, 1781 Jun 29 (Box 6, Folder 380)
    - Letters to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, [1780?]-[post 1783] (Box 6, Folder 381)
    - Letters to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, 1785-90 (Box 6, Folder 382)
    - Letters to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, 1791-93 (Box 6, Folder 383)
    - Letter to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, 1796 Jul 17 (Box 6, Folder 384)
    - Letters to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, 1799-1812 (Box 6, Folder 385)
    - Letters to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, 1813-15 (Box 6, Folder 386)
    - Letter to his sisters, Frances, Susanna, and Charlotte, [1781 May 21?] (Box 6, Folder 387)
    - Letters to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, 1816-17 (Box 6, Folder 388)
    - Letter to Mr. Asperne, 1817 May 2 (Box 6, Folder 389)
    - Letter to Edmund Henry Barker, 1813 Dec 18 (Box 6, Folder 390)
    - Letter to Shute Barrington, [ca. 1795-1813] (Box 6, Folder 391)
    - Verses, to Dr. Beattie, 1779 Apr 12 (Box 6, Folder 392)
    - Letters to Charles James Blomfield, Bishop of London, 1810-13 (Box 6, Folder 393)
    - Letter to [Josiah Boydell], 1816 May 9 (Box 6, Folder 394)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1808 Jul 7 (Box 6, Folder 395)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1804 (Box 6, Folder 396)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1805 Feb-Mar (Box 6, Folder 397)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1805 Apr-May (Box 6, Folder 398)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1805 Jun-Dec (Box 6, Folder 399)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1806 Jan-Mar (Box 6, Folder 400)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1806 May-Aug (Box 6, Folder 401)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1806 Aug-Dec (Box 6, Folder 402)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1807 Jan (Box 6, Folder 403)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1807 Feb-May (Box 6, Folder 404)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1807 Nov-Dec (Box 6, Folder 405)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1808 Jan-Feb (Box 6, Folder 406)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1808 Mar-Jun (Box 6, Folder 407)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1808 Aug-Sep (Box 6, Folder 408)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1808 Nov-Dec (Box 6, Folder 409)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1809 Jan (Box 6, Folder 410)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1809 Feb-Mar (Box 6, Folder 411)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1809 May (Box 6, Folder 412)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1809 Jun-Jul (Box 6, Folder 413)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1809 Sep-Oct (Box 6, Folder 414)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1809 Dec (Box 6, Folder 415)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1810 Apr-May (Box 6, Folder 416)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1810 Jun (Box 6, Folder 417)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1810 Jul (Box 6, Folder 418)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1810 Aug-[post 1809] (Box 6, Folder 419)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1811 Jan-Aug (Box 6, Folder 420)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1812 (Box 6, Folder 421)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1813 Feb-Aug (Box 6, Folder 422)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1813 Sep (Box 6, Folder 423)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1813 Oct (Box 6, Folder 424)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1814-15 (Box 6, Folder 425)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1816-17 (Box 6, Folder 426)
    - Letter to Fanny Burney, [1780] (Box 6, Folder 427)
    - Letter to his wife, Rosette (Rose) Burney, 1800 Jan 9 (Box 6, Folder 428)
    - Letters to Rosette (Rose) Burney, 1815-16 (Box 6, Folder 429)
    - Letters to [Thomas Cadell] and to Cadell & Davies, Inc., 1788-1800 (Box 6, Folder 430)
    - Letter to [Alexander] Chalmers, 1803 Feb 26 (Box 6, Folder 431)
    - Letter to Richard Clark, 1807 Apr 21 (Box 7, Folder 432)
    - Letter to George Dyer, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 433)
    - Letter to Edward Foss, Jr., 1814 Jul 26 (Box 7, Folder 434)
    - Letter to Francis Freeling, 1807-10 (Box 7, Folder 435)
    - Letter to John Gillies, 1817 Sep 13 (Box 7, Folder 436)
    - Letters to Abercrombie Gordon, 1779-1808 (Box 7, Folder 437)
    - Letter to [R.] Gray, 1807 Jul 11 (Box 7, Folder 438)
    - Letter to George Griffiths, 1812 Jun 20 (Box 7, Folder 438a)
    - Letter to Mr. Hatch, 1806 Sep 4 (Box 7, Folder 439)
    - Letter to Sir Benjamin Hobhouse, Bart., 1814 May 22 (Box 7, Folder 440)
    - Letter to [William Howley], Bishop of London, 1817 Jun 12 (Box 7, Folder 441)
    - Journal-letter to his sister, Susanna Elizabeth (Burney) Philips, 1780 (Box 7, Folder 442)
    - Letters to Patrick Kelly, 1812, 1816 (Box 7, Folder 443)
    - Letter to [George Henry Law], 1814 Feb 24 (Box 7, Folder 444)
    - Letter to Robert Lawless of Cadell & Davies, 1793 Aug 20 (Box 7, Folder 445)
    - Letter to [Edward Malone], 1799 Aug 16 (Box 7, Folder 446)
    - Letter to [Charles Manners-Sutton], 1807 Dec 17 (Box 7, Folder 447)
    - Letter to Mr. Mason, 1813 Jul 12 (Box 7, Folder 448)
    - Letter to Charles Mathews, 1816 Jan 21 (Box 7, Folder 449)
    - Letters to Thomas Maurice, 1814, 1817 (Box 7, Folder 450)
    - Letter to John Nichols, 1808 Nov 27 (Box 7, Folder 451)
    - Letter to the Earl of Findlater, 1781 Aug (Box 7, Folder 452)
    - Letter to William Parsons, 1806 Aug 28 (Box 7, Folder 453)
    - Letter to Susanna Elizabeth (Burney) Phillips, 1781 Apr 20 (Box 7, Folder 454)
    - Letter to Mr. Pridden, 1809 Mar 24 (Box 7, Folder 455)
    - Letter to G. Priestley, 1808 May 5 (Box 7, Folder 456)
    - Letter to Dr. Samuel Parr, 1790 Jan 6 (Box 7, Folder 457)
    - Letter to Isaac Reed, 1788 Aug 23 (Box 7, Folder 458)
    - Letter to Mr. Richardson, 1815 Jun 9 (Box 7, Folder 459)
    - Letter to J. Robinson, bookseller, 1805 Jan 18 (Box 7, Folder 460)
    - Letter to William F. Rose, 1811 Apr 11 (Box 7, Folder 461)
    - Letter to Sir John St. Aubyn, 1817 May 29 (Box 7, Folder 462)
    - Letter to William Shield, 1817 Aug 24 (Box 7, Folder 463)
    - Letter to William Sotheby, [1800 Apr 7] (Box 7, Folder 464)
    - Letter to Richard Twining, 1805 May 8 (Box 7, Folder 465)
    - Letter to Thomas Twining, 1789-99 (Box 7, Folder 466)
    - Letter to unnamed recipient, 1806 Feb 2 (Box 7, Folder 467)
    - Letter to unnamed recipient, 1814 Mar 16 (Box 7, Folder 468)
    - Letter to unnamed recipient, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 469)
    - Agreement to meet annually with Thomas Burgess and Richard Porson, [1792] (Box 7, Folder 470)
    - Certificate of admission to the rectory of Hinton, 1811 Jul 28 (Box 7, Folder 471)
    - Declaration of conformity to the liturgical conformity, 1811 Feb 21 (Box 7, Folder 472)
    - Dedication to Richard Porson, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 473)
    - Epitaph on an abbé, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 474)
    - Extracts from scholastic records concerning Charles Burney, D.D., [1814] (Box 7, Folder 475)
    - Fragment: holograph verse of 14 lines, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 476)
    - Grace: from the French: holograph, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 477)
    - Impromptu, on the horses of the Prince of Wales: holograph verses, 1805 Jul 30 (Box 7, Folder 478)
    - Inscription for a hunting cottage, in Mar Forest, 1780 Aug 27 (Box 7, Folder 479)
    - A Letter to F. I. H. W.: verse, 1778 Feb 3 (Box 7, Folder 480)
    - Literary memoranda (Box 7, Folder 481)
    - Memoranda on Dr. Parr's approval of a Greek Thesaurus-Lexicon (Box 7, Folder 482)
    - Memorandum headed "p. 320 Ellis" (Box 7, Folder 483)
    - The Monk's Tale, paraphrased, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 484)
    - Notes on Aristophanes, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 485)
    - Notes on Charles Burney's Funeral, [1818] (Box 7, Folder 486)
    - On a Late Resignation: Verses on Jemmy Sleepe, 1781 (Box 7, Folder 487)
    - Poetical miscellany: verses by various authors, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 488)
    - Proposals for the Porson Prize, [1811] (Box 7, Folder 489)
    - Rondeau: poem, 1795 Jan 24 (Box 7, Folder 490)
    - Signature: cut from a letter, 1817 Aug 7 (Box 7, Folder 491)
    - To Rosette: verse, 1783 Jan 1 (Box 7, Folder 492)
    - Portraits, etc., n.d. (Box 7, Folder 493)
  - BURNEY, CHARLES, IV, 1815-1907
    - Letter to W. B. Ady, 1865 May 15 (Box 7, Folder 494)
    - Letters to Mrs. Charles Parr Burney [Francis Bentley Young], 1825-28 (Box 7, Folder 495)
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1829 Jun 3 (Box 7, Folder 496)
    - Letter to Mrs. Gill, [1903] (Box 7, Folder 497)
    - Letter to Roundell Palmer, Earl of Suffolk, [1886 Aug] (Box 7, Folder 498)
    - Certificate of ordination to priesthood, 1839 Dec 22 (Box 7, Folder 499)
    - Epitaph for Charles Parr Burney, 1864 (Box 7, Folder 500)
  - BURNEY, CHARLES PARR, 1785-1864
    - Letter to James Asperne, 1818 Jan 6 (Box 7, Folder 501)
    - Letter to Richard Best, 1831 Oct 7 (Box 7, Folder 502)
    - Letter to W. K. Boston, 1850 Oct 4 (Box 7, Folder 503)
    - Letter to Mr. [William Thomas] Brande, 1844 Apr 27 (Box 7, Folder 504)
    - Letter to Edward Wedlake Brayley, 1822 Mar 19 (Box 7, Folder 505)
    - Letter to the Rev. Henry Brown, 1851 Jan 1 (Box 7, Folder 506)
    - Letter to [Jacob Henry] Burn, 1822 Sep 26 (Box 7, Folder 507)
    - Letter to Miss Annie Warner [Burney], 1837 Jun 19 (Box 7, Folder 508)
    - Letters to Charles Burney IV, 1850-58 (Box 7, Folder 509)
    - Letters to Charles Burney IV, 1859-61, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 510)
    - Letters to his daughter, Ellen Burney, 1857-60 (Box 7, Folder 511)
    - Letters to Frances Bentley (Young) Burney, 1811-12 (Box 7, Folder 512)
    - Letters to Henry Bannerman Burney, 1858-59 (Box 7, Folder 513)
    - Letter to Rosette [Rose] Burney, [1797 Apr] (Box 7, Folder 514)
    - Letter to Rosette (Rose) Burney, 1799 Jan 17 (Box 7, Folder 515)
    - Letters to Rosette (Rose) Burney, 1799-1802 (Box 7, Folder 516)
    - Letters to Rosette (Rose) Burney, 1803-05 (Box 7, Folder 517)
    - Letters to Rosette (Rose) Burney, 1806-09 (Box 7, Folder 518)
    - Letters to Rosette (Rose) Burney, 1818 (Box 7, Folder 519)
    - Letter to Mr. Chapman, 1837 Jun 12 (Box 7, Folder 520)
    - Letter to Dominic Paul Colnaghi, 1862 Sep 29 (Box 7, Folder 521)
    - Letter to William Daniel Conybeare, 1848 Dec 30 (Box 7, Folder 522)
    - Letter to Anthony Vandyke Copley Fielding, 1840 Nov 5 (Box 7, Folder 523)
    - Letter to Edward Foss, Jr., 1815 Jun 9 (Box 7, Folder 524)
    - Letter to the Rev. Samuel Whitlock Gandy, 1840 Jan 1 (Box 8, Folder 525)
    - Letter to Mr. Harvey, 1851 Apr 28 (Box 8, Folder 526)
    - Letter to Thomas Hepworth, 1853 Jul 18 (Box 8, Folder 527)
    - Letter to Mrs. Hayman, 1842 Dec 5 (Box 8, Folder 528)
    - Letter to Hrs. Hudson, 1850 Feb 16 (Box 8, Folder 529)
    - Letter to W. F. John Kaye, 1853 Feb 28 (Box 8, Folder 530)
    - Letters to Messrs. Lackington, 1814, 1821 (Box 8, Folder 531)
    - Letter to John Lynes, 1825 Jan 31 (Box 8, Folder 532)
    - Letters to John Mitford, 1841-48 (Box 8, Folder 533)
    - Letters to [John Nichols], 1818-30 (Box 8, Folder 534)
    - Letters to Samuel Parr, 1821-1825 (Box 8, Folder 535)
    - Letter to Henry Philpott, Vice-Chancellor of Cambridge, 1857 May 23 (Box 8, Folder 536)
    - Letter to Mrs. Pond, 1843 Feb 7 (Box 8, Folder 537)
    - Letter to George Fennel Robson, 1823 Apr 28 (Box 8, Folder 538)
    - Letter to the President of the Royal College of Surgeons, 1828 Feb 8 (Box 8, Folder 539)
    - Letter to James St. Aubyn, 1817 May 29 (Box 8, Folder 540)
    - Letter to Mrs. Stewart, 1844 Nov 28 (Box 8, Folder 541)
    - Letters to John Taylor, 1824-25 (Box 8, Folder 542)
    - Letter to [James Thomson], 1820 Aug 19 (Box 8, Folder 543)
    - Letter to Mr. Triphook, 1827 Apr 4 (Box 8, Folder 544)
    - Letters to the Rev. Richard W. White, 1825-29 (Box 8, Folder 545)
    - Letter to unnamed recipient, 1819 Nov 17 (Box 8, Folder 546)
    - Letter to [the uncle of a pupil], 1832 Dec 29 (Box 8, Folder 547)
    - Letter to an unnamed recipient, 1833 Apr 2 (Box 8, Folder 548)
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney from an unnamed correspondent, [post 1819] (Box 8, Folder 549)
    - Copy of a Robert Southey epitaph, [1830] (Box 8, Folder 550)
    - Anecdotes concerning Sir George H. Rose, [1864?] (Box 8, Folder 551)
    - Certificate of his ordination to the Diaconate, 1810 Dec 21 (Box 8, Folder 552)
    - Certificate of his subscription to certain ecclesiastical articles, 1811 Feb 21 (Box 8, Folder 553)
    - Subscription to the regulations of the University, 1804 Jul 30 (Box 8, Folder 554)
    - Passport issued to Burney for travel in France and Switzerland, 1816 Jul 9 (Box 8, Folder 555)
    - Sermon: holograph, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 556)
    - Signature, cut from a letter, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 557)
  - BURNEY, EDWARD FRANCESCO, 1760-1848
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., [ca. 1780] Mar 4 (Box 8, Folder 558)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1821-32 (Box 8, Folder 559)
    - Portraits, etc., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 560)
  - BURNEY, EDWARD KAYE, 1817-1880
    - Letter to Anne Jane Warner (Burney), 1837 Jan 10 (Box 8, Folder 561)
    - Letter to his mother, Frances Bentley (Young) Burney, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 562)
  - BURNEY, ELLEN HODGESON, 1820-1911
    - Letter to her father, Charles Parr Burney, 1857 Oct 20 (Box 8, Folder 563)
  - BURNEY, ESTHER (BURNEY), 1749-1832
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1800-06, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 564)
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1821 May 8 (Box 8, Folder 565)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1813 Jan 25 (Box 8, Folder 566)
    - Letter to Frances Bentley (Young) Burney, 1827 May 10 (Box 8, Folder 567)
    - Letter to Rosette (Rose) Burney, 1817 Dec 30 (Box 8, Folder 568)
  - BURNEY, FRANCES BENTLEY (YOUNG), 1792-1878
    - Letter to Anne [Warner] (later Mrs. C. E. Burney), 1836 Apr 10 (Box 8, Folder 569)
    - Letter to an unnamed recipient, 1871 May 5 (Box 8, Folder 570)
  - BURNEY, HENRY BANNERMAN, 1819-1890
    - Letter to Frances Bentley (Young) Burney, 1857 [Jul 21] (Box 8, Folder 571)
  - BURNEY, JAMES, 1750-1821
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., [1804], 1815 (Box 8, Folder 572)